# ryan.amalfitano

### **Profile**

Web Design professional with strengths in web development and design, knowledge of various core languages and best practices, as well as Search Engine Optimization (SEO) and Information Architecture (IA) techniques; in-depth experience with the WordPress content management system (CMS) and custom theme development.

#### Education

2008 – 2012 Abbey Park High School

2012 – 2014 Georgian College – Web Animation and Design

(Ontario College Diploma, Co-op)

2012 Georgian College – Dean's List

2015 – 2019 Brock University – Interactive Arts and Sciences (BA)

## **Training and Experience**

Web Languages Fluent in HTML5, CSS3, PHP, JavaScript, and JQuery

Capable in MySQL, Angular.js, Bootstrap

Desktop Languages Capable in C++

Development Programs

Fluent in Adobe Photoshop and Dreamweaver Capable in Adobe Illustrator, InDesign, and Flash

Web Applications Fluent with WordPress

Capable with ASP.net and CakePHP

Design Skills Keen design sense

Knowledge of IA and SEO techniques

Exemplary creative and formal writing techniques

Workplace Skills Strong communication and teamwork skills

Sharp attention to detail

Independent and stays on-task

# Work Experience

2013 – Present Gel Creative – Head Web Developer

## **Voluntary Experience**

2012 Cancer Society – Daffodil Days

2009 – 2011 Fareshare Food Drive – Halloween for Hunger